Wonder by RJ palasio fortune favors the Bold MR Brown's DECEMBER PRECEPT was: Fortune
favors the bold. We were all supposed to write a paragraph about some time in our
lives when we did something very brave and how, because of it, something good
happened to us. I thought about this a lot, to be truthful. I have to say that I
think the bravest thing I ever did was become friends with August. But I
couldn’t write about that, of course. I was afraid we’d have to read these out
loud, or Mr Brown would put them up on the bulletin board like he does
sometimes. So, instead, I wrote this lame thing about how I used to be afraid of
the ocean when I was little. It was dumb but I couldn’t think of anything else. I
wonder what August wrote about. He probably had a lot of things to choose from private school
MY PARENTS ARE not rich. I say this because people sometimes think that
everyone who goes to private school is rich, but that isn’t true with us. Dad’s a
teacher and Mom’s a social worker, which means they don’t have those kinds of
jobs where people make gazillions of dollars. We used to have a car, but we
sold it when Jamie started kindergarten at Beacher Prep. We don’t live in a big
townhouse or in one of those dman buildings along the park. We live on the
top floor of a five-story walk up we rent from an old lady named Donna Petra
all the way on the “other” side of Broadway. That’s “code” for the section of
North River Heights where people don’t want to park their cars. Me and Jamie
share a room. I over hear my parents talk about things like “Can we do without an
air conditioner one more year?” or “Maybe I can work two jobs this
summer.” So today at recess I was hanging out with Julian and Henry and Miles.
Julian, who everyone knows is rich, was like, “I hate that I have to go back to
Paris this Christmas. It’s so boring!” “Dude, but it’s, like, Paris I said
like an idiot. “Believe me, it’s so boring,” he said. “My grandmother lives in this
house in the middle of nowhere. It’s like an hour away from Paris in this tiny,
tiny, tiny village. I swear to God, nothing happens there! I mean, it’s like, oh wow,
there’s another fly on the wall! Look, there’s a new dog sleeping on the
sidewalk yipp I laughed. Sometimes Julian could be very funny. “Though my parents are talking
about throwing a big party this year instead of going to Paris. I hope so. What
are you doing over break?” said Julian.
“Just hanging out,” I said. “You’re so lucky,” he said. “I hope it snows again,” I answered.
“I I got this new sled that is so amazing.” I was about to tell them about Lightning
but Miles started talking first. “I got a new sled, too!” he said. “My dad got it from
homah Schlemmer. It’s so state-of-the-art How could a sled be
state-ofthe-art said Julian. “It was like $800 or something.”
“Whoa!” “We should all go sledding and have a race down Skeleton Hill,” I said the
hill is so lame,” answered Julian. “Are you kidding?” I said. “Some kid broke his neck
there. That’s why they call it Skeleton Hill.” Julian narrowed his eyes and looked
at me like I was the biggest in the world. “It’s called Skeleton Hill
because it was an ancient Indian burial ground, duh,” he said. “Anyway, it should be
called Garbage Hill now, it’s so freaking junky. Last time I was there it was so
gross, like with soda cans and broken bottles and stuff.” He shook his head. “I
left my old sled there,” said Miles. “It was the crappiest piece of junk— —and someone
took it, too!” “Maybe a hobo wanted to go sleding laughed Julian. “Where did you
leave it?” I said. “By the big rock at the
bottom of the hill. And I went back the next day and it was gone. I couldn’t
believe somebody actually took it!” “Here’s what we can do,” said Julian.
“Next time it snows, my dad could drive us up up to the golf course in Winchester
that makes Skeleton Hill look like nothing. Hey, Jack, where are you going?” I
had started to walk away. “I’ve got to get a book out of my locker,” I
lied. I just wanted to get away from them
fast. I didn’t want anyone to know that I was the “hobo” who had taken the
sled in science I’M NOT THE greatest student in the world. I know some kids
actually like school, but I honestly can’t say I do. I like some parts of
school, like PE and computer class. And lunch in recess. But all in all, I’d be
fine without school. And the thing I hate the most about school is all the
homework we get. It’s not enough that we have to sit through class after class
and try to stay awake while they fill our heads with all this stuff we will
probably never need to know, like how to figure out the surface area of a cube or
what the difference is between kinetic and potential energy. I’m like, who cares?
I’ve never, ever heard my parents say the word “kinetic” in my entire life! I hate
science the most out of all my classes it get so much work it’s not even funny!
And the teacher Miss Ruben is so strict about everything— —even the way we write
our headings on the top of our papers! I once got two points off a homework
assignment because I didn’t put the date on top. Crazy stuff. When me and August
were still friends, I was doing okay in science because August sat next to me
and always let me copy his notes. August has the neatest handwriting of anybody
I’ve ever seen who’s a boy. Even his script is neat: up and down perfectly,
with really small round loopy letters.
But now that we’re ex-friends, it’s bad
because I can’t ask him to let me copy his notes anymore. So I was kind of
scrambling today, trying to take notes about what Miss Ruben was saying (my
handwriting is awful), when all of a sudden she started talking about the
fifth grade science fair project, how we all had to choose a science project to
work on. While she was saying this, I was thinking, We just finished the freaking
Egypt project, now we have to start a whole new thing? And then in my head I
was going, Oh no like that kid in Home Alone with his mouth hanging open and
his hands on his face. That was the face I was making on the inside. And then I
thought of those pictures of melting ghost Face I’ve seen somewhere, where the
mouths are open wide and they’re screaming. And then all of a sudden this
picture flew into my head, this memory, and I knew what Summer had meant by
“bleeding scream.” It’s so weird how it all just came to me in this flash. Someone in
Home Room had dressed up in a Bleeding Scream costume on Halloween. I remember
seeing him a few desks away from me. And then I remember not seeing him again. Oh
man man. It was August! All of this hit me in science class while the teacher was
talking. Oh man. I’d been talking to Julian about August. Oh man. Now I
understood! I was so mean. I don’t even
know why. I’m not even sure what I said,
but it was bad. It was only a minute or
two. It’s just that I knew Julian and everybody thought I was so weird for
hanging out with August all the time, and I felt stupid. And I don’t know why I
said that stuff. I just was going along. I was stupid. I am stupid. Oh God. He was
supposed to come as Boba Fett! I would never have said that stuff in front of
Boba fit But that was him, that Bleeding Scream sitting at the desk looking over
at us. The long white mask with the fake squirting blood. The mouth open wide. Like
the ghoul was crying. That with him. I felt like I was going to
puke Partners I DIDN’T HEAR a word of what Miss Ruben was saying after that.
Blah blah blah science fair project. Blah blah blah. Partners. Blah blah. It was like
the way grown-ups talk in Charlie Brown movies. Like someone talking underwater
wahah Then all of a sudden Miss Ruben started pointing to kids around the
class Reed and Tristan, Maya and Max, Charlotte and zamina August and Jack.” She
pointed to us when she said this. “Miles and Amos, Julian and Henry Savannah and I
didn’t hear the rest. “Huh?” I said. The bell rang. “So don’t forget to get together
with your partners to choose a project from the list, guys!” said Miss Ruben as
everyone started taking off. I looked up at August, but he had already put his
backpack on and was practically out the door. I must have had a stupid look on my
face because Julian came over and said: “Looks like you and your best bud are
partners.” He was smirking when he said this. I hated him so much right then.
“Hello, earth to Jack Will?” he said when I didn’t answer him. “Shut up, Julian.” I was
putting my loose leaf binder away in my backpack and just wanted him away from
me. “You must be so bummed you got stuck with him,” he said. “You should tell Miss
ruin you want to switch partners. I bet
she’d let you.” “No she wouldn’t,” I said. “Ask
her.” “No, I don’t want to miss ran Julian said, turning around and raising his hand
at the same time Miss Rubin was erasing the chalkboard at the front of the room.
She turned when she heard her name. “No, Julian!” I whisper
screamed What is it, boys?” she she asked impatiently. “Could we switch partners if
we wanted to?” said Julian, looking very innocent. “Me and Jack had this science
fair project idea we wanted to work on together. “Well, I guess we could arrange
that she started to say. “No, it’s okay Miss Ruben I said quickly, heading out
the door. “Bye!” Julian ran after me why' you do that?” he said, catching up to me at
the stairs. “We could have been part partners. You don’t have to be friends
with that freak if you don’t want to be,
you know. And that’s when I punched him.
Right in the mouth detention SOME THINGS YOU just can’t
explain. You don’t even try. You don’t know where to start. All your sentences
would jumble up like a giant knot if you open your mouth. Any words you used would
come out wrong. “Jack, this is very, very serious,” Mr. Tushman was saying. I was in
his office, sitting on a chair across from his desk and looking at this
picture of a pumpkin on the wall behind him. “Kids get expelled for this kind of
thing, Jack! I know you’re a good kid and
I don’t want that to happen, but you have to explain yourself.” “This is so not like
you, Jack,” said Mom. She had come from work as soon as they had called her. I could
tell she was going back and forth between being really mad and really
surprised. “I thought you and Julian were friends,” said Mr. Tushman. “We’re not
friends,” I said. My arms were crossed in front of me. “But to punch someone in the mouth,
Jack?” said Mom, raising her voice. “I mean, what were you thinking?” She looked at Mr.
Tushman. “Honestly, he’s never hit anyone before. He’s just not like that.” “Julian’s
mouth was a bleeding, Jack,” said Mr.
Tushman. “You knocked out a tooth, did you know that?” “It was just a baby tooth,” I
said. “Jack!” said Mom, shaking her head.
“That’s what Nurse Molly said!” “You’re missing the point!” Mom yelled. “I just want
to know why,” said Mr. Tushman, raising his shoulders. “It’ll just make everything worse,” I
sigh Just tell me, Jack.” I shrugged but I did didn’t say anything. I just couldn’t.
If I told him that Julian had called August a freak, then he’d go talk to
Julian about it, then Julian would tell him how I had bad mouthed August, too, and
everybody would find out about it. “Jack!” said Mom. I started to cry. “I’m sorry Mr.
Tushman raised his eyebrows and nodded, but he didn’t say anything. Instead, he
kind of blew into his hands, like you do when your hands are cold.
“Jack,” he said, “I don’t really know what to
say here. I mean, you punched a kid. We have rules about that kind of thing, you
know? Automatic expulsion. And you’re not even trying to explain
yourself.” I was crying a lot by now, and the second Mom put her arms around me, I
started to ball let um said Mr. Tushman, taking his
glasses off to clean them, “let’s do this, Jack. We’re out for winter break as of
next week anyway. How about you stay home for the rest of this week, and then after
winter break you’ll come back and everything will be fresh and brand new.
Clean slate, so to speak.” “Am I being suspended?” I sniffled.
“Well,” he said, shrugging, “technically yes, but it’s only for a couple of days. And
I’ll tell you what. While you’re at home,
you take the time to think about what’s happened. And if you want to write me a
letter explaining what happened, and a letter to Julian apologizing, then we
won’t even put any of this in your permanent record, okay? You go home and
talk about it with your mom and dad, and maybe in the morning you’ll figure it
all out a bit more.” “That sounds like a good plan, Mr. Tushman,” said Mom, nodding.
“Thank you.” “Everything is going to be okay,” said Mr. Tushman, walking over to the door,
which was closed. “I know you’re a nice kid, Jack. And I know that sometimes even
nice kids do dumb things, right?” He opened the door. “Thank you for being so
understanding,” said Mom, shaking his hand at the door. “No problem.” He leaned over
and told her something quietly that I couldn’t hear. “I know, thank you,” said Mom,
nodding. “So, kiddo,” he said to me, putting his hands on my shoulders. “Think about
what you’ve done, okay? And have a great holiday. Happy Hanukkah Merry Christmas!
Happy Quanza I wiped my nose with my sleeve and started walking out the door.
“Say thank you to Mr. Tushman,” said Mom, tapping my shoulder. I stopped and turned
around, but I couldn’t look at him. “Thank you, Mr. Tushman,” I said. “Bye, Jack,” he
answered. Then I walked out the door season's greetings WEIRDLY ENOUGH, WHEN we got
back home and Mom brought in the mail, there were holiday cards from both
Julian’s family and August’s family.
Julian’s holiday card was a picture of Julian wearing a tie, looking like he was
about to go to the opera or something.
August’s holiday card was of a cute old dog wearing reindeer antlers, a red nose,
and red booties. There was a cartoon bubble above the dog’s head that read ho
ho ho On the inside of the card it read: To the Will family Peace on Earth Love,
Nate Isabelle Olivia, August (and Daisy) “Cute card, huh?” I said to Mom, who
had hardly said a word to me all the way home. I think she honestly just didn’t
know what to say. “That must be their dog,” I
said. “Do you want to tell me what’s going on inside your head, Jack?” she answered me
seriously. “I bet you they put a picture of their dog on the card every year,” I
said. She took the card from my hands and looked at the picture carefully and she
raised her eyebrows and her shoulders and gave me back the
card. “We’re very lucky, Jack. There’s so much we take for
granted. “I know,” I said. I knew what she was talking about without her having to
say it. “I heard that Julian’s mom actually Photoshopped Augusta's face out
of the class picture when she got it. She gave a copy to a couple of the other
moms.” “That’s just awful,” said Mom. “People are just they’re not always so great.” “I
know.” “Is that why you hit Julian?” “No.” And then I told her why I punched Julian. And
I told her that August was my ex-friend now. And I told her about
[Music]
Halloween hi everyone thanks for listening please remember to like and
share become a channel member and we'll see you next time
[Music]